Ritesh Mahajan

Software Engineer

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am an experienced IT professional with 2 years in Frontend Development using React JS and Backend Development skills in Node JS, Express JS, and MongoDB. Successfully delivers projects on time. Proficient in GitHub, GraphQL, Postman API, and Unit Testing.

EXPERIENCE

Undocked Technology India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru — Software Engineer

Jan 2024 - March 2024

- Worked in the supply chain domain.
- Design and develop after gathering requirements from the Lead and PM.
- Developing REST APIs and Handling admin and core product services.

Undocked Technology India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru — Associate Software Engineer

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

- Worked in the supply chain domain.
- Design and develop after gathering requirements from the Lead and PM.

Undocked Technology India Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru — Trainee Engineer Intern

May 2022 - Dec 2022

- Developed responsive UI components using React.js.
- Optimize code quality and performance of web apps.

EDUCATION

- Software Training and Development Centre, Kochi
 - PG Diploma in Advanced Computing April 2022
- Shri Gulabrao Deokar College of Engineering, Jalgaon

BE in Computer Science - May 2021

Shri Gulabrao Deokar College of Diploma, Jalgaon

Diploma in Computer Science - May 2018

LANGUAGES

Marathi, Hindi, English

PROJECT DETAILS

Cargomatic — Logistics and Supply Chain Management System

Cargomatic is a top marketplace for local freight, connecting big companies with nearby truck drivers for quick and efficient shipping. They offer various shipping methods like drayage and home delivery in real-time, making it easy for businesses to move goods smoothly.

Student Attendance Management System — *Managing student attendance*

We have built a Student Attendance Management System during the PGDAC Course in that Managing student attendance during lecture periods has become a difficult challenge. Manual calculation of attendance produces errors and wastes a lot of time. This proposed system manages the students' attendance in a web portal and the records of the attendance will be stored in a database. This system will use MongoDB for databases. The template of the website will be built using Mern Stack.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages
 - JavaScript
- Web Development
 - HTML, CSS
- Database
 - MongoDB
- Frameworks
 - React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Graphql
- Libraries and Software
 - Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 01/02/1997Nationality : Indian

• Address : At. Veruli Burd, Tal. Pachora, Dist. Jalgaon

• Linkedin : www.linkedin.com/in/ritesh-mahajan-a74a33200

Github : https://github.com/rdmahajan12